<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>article on 0xNinja - My blog</title><link>http://example.org/tags/article/</link><description>Recent content in article on 0xNinja - My blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 14:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SQLi lab solutions</title><link>http://example.org/posts/sqli-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/sqli-lab/</guid><description>Some weeks ago I created a trainning lab for SQL injections called SQLi lab. And I will go through all levels in this blog post, explainning the expected way to solve each of them.
The lab currently contains 5 levels, and I will update this post as I add more of them 👍
Installation The GitHub repository is at https://github.com/OxNinja/SQLi-lab if you want more information.
First I clone the lab in a folder, add its IP to my hosts file for conveignance, and then build it with the given script:</description></item><item><title>Setup your database with Docker</title><link>http://example.org/posts/setup-your-database-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/setup-your-database-with-docker/</guid><description>Yeah, I wanted to do one of those for a long time 😁
So, we have to stay at home for the moment, I decided to make a &amp;ldquo;walkthrough&amp;rdquo; about something I used sometimes and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember all the commands. So, let&amp;rsquo;s build our MySQL database within a Docker container 🐳 !
Get the Docker image I will be using the mysql image from the Docker hub.
1 docker pull mysql Run the container For further details, you can read the official documentation for the image on Docker hub.</description></item><item><title>La vulnérabilité Shellshock</title><link>http://example.org/posts/la-vuln%C3%A9rabilite-shellshock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/la-vuln%C3%A9rabilite-shellshock/</guid><description>Shellshock est une vulnérabilité présente dans bash 4.3 et antérieur. Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une vulnérabilité logicielle qui se base sur de l&amp;rsquo;injection de commande en passant par les variables d&amp;rsquo;environement. C&amp;rsquo;est vachement cool car elle mène à une bonne grosse RCE des familles, donc c&amp;rsquo;est pas négligeable 😘.
Statistiques Quelques statistiques afin d&amp;rsquo;illustrer la portée et l&amp;rsquo;attention portée de la vulnérabilité.
Shellshock a beaucoup été à la mode quand elle est sortie, énormément de trafic a été généré par des botnets lors de tentatives d&amp;rsquo;exploitation de la vulnérabilité.</description></item></channel></rss>