<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>0xNinja - My blog</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/</link><description>Recent content on 0xNinja - My blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 13:00:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0xninja.fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🪛 Build your own mechanical keyboard</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/build-your-own-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 13:00:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/build-your-own-keyboard/</guid><description>A simple and quick summary on how to build a mechnical keyboard on your own from scratch.</description></item><item><title>You want to start to `pwn`?</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/start-pwn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 13:00:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/start-pwn/</guid><description>So you want to start to pwn, don&amp;rsquo;t you? Well, I did too! Those are my notes on the past year of binary exploitation.</description></item><item><title>How to install Archlinux</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/install-archlinux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 11:06:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/install-archlinux/</guid><description>I recently installed once again Archlinux on a laptop. Let me explain how to do so.</description></item><item><title>📦 HTB - Schooled</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-schooled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-schooled/</guid><description>Cool box, not too CTF-like and real-life applicable, my first FreeBSD 😄 But root part was too quick.
TL;DR XSS to steal Moodle creds of teacher, privesc as manager and then RCE. Get MySQL in config file, dump users and get password hash. Break the hash with john to ssh as user. Common pkg install exploit for root.
Footholds # Nmap 7.91 scan initiated Mon Aug 2 22:40:05 2021 as: nmap -A -p- -T4 -o nmap.</description></item><item><title>🚀 TL;DR - pacman</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-pacman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-pacman/</guid><description>The famous packet manager for Archlinux</description></item><item><title>🚀 TL;DR - nmap</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-nmap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-nmap/</guid><description>Maybe the most used tool when it comes to network discovery and port knocking.</description></item><item><title>🚀 TL;DR - Docker</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-docker/</guid><description>Wow you don&amp;rsquo;t know yet what Docker is? 🤔 Let me introduce you this beautiful containerization tool!</description></item><item><title>🚀 TL;DR - What is the 'TL;DR' series?</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-tldr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/tldr-tldr/</guid><description>So I came up with this basic concept: TL;DR. But what is it exactly?
The TL;DR series The main idea is to share some knowledge in a quick and concise way, such as a RUMP but written on a file. It is like a writeup speedrunning-ish style of writting. And maybe because I am kind of lazy sometimes.
The goal here is to write small articles about a subject I like, a new technique learnt, or anything that is not worth a full and detailed article.</description></item><item><title>Free space on disk for Linux distros</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/free-space-on-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/free-space-on-disk/</guid><description>Recently I wanted to run a MySQL Docker container and encountered a tragical error:
simple_db | 2021-03-25 10:54:04+00:00 [Note] [Entrypoint]: Switching to dedicated user 'mysql' simple_db | 2021-03-25 10:54:04+00:00 [Note] [Entrypoint]: Entrypoint script for MySQL Server 5.7.31-1debian10 started. simple_db | 2021-03-25 10:54:04+00:00 [Note] [Entrypoint]: Initializing database files simple_db | 2021-03-25T10:54:04.578298Z 0 [Warning] TIMESTAMP with implicit DEFAULT value is deprecated. Please use --explicit_defaults_for_timestamp server option (see documentation for more details). simple_db | 2021-03-25T10:54:04.</description></item><item><title>📦 HTB - Ready</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-ready/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-ready/</guid><description>Cool box, maybe too easy for a medium? Got reverse shell in minutes, but stuck for root&amp;rsquo;s password for hours 😅
TL;DR Gitlab RCE, get reverse shell. Privesc with cleartext root password, escape Docker to own the box.
Footholds nmap Starting Nmap 7.80 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2021-03-14 16:00 UTC Nmap scan report for 10.10.10.220 Host is up (0.035s latency). Not shown: 998 closed ports PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.</description></item><item><title>SQLi lab solutions</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/sqli-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/sqli-lab/</guid><description>Some weeks ago I created a trainning lab for SQL injections called SQLi lab. And I will go through all levels in this blog post, explainning the expected way to solve each of them.
The lab currently contains 5 levels, and I will update this post as I add more of them 👍
Installation The GitHub repository is at https://github.com/OxNinja/SQLi-lab if you want more information.
First I clone the lab in a folder, add its IP to my hosts file for conveignance, and then build it with the given script:</description></item><item><title>📦 HTB - Magic</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-magic/</guid><description>TL;DR HTTP redirect bypass (unintended 😁), PHP code execution through file upload to get a reverse shell. User with hardcoded SQL credentials on server, privesc with custom binary with no $PATH check.
As I am an idiot, I reinstalled my distribution without making a backup of my files 🙈 So I don&amp;rsquo;t have any screenshot or payloads I used for this box to show you
Footholds With a basic nmap we found only two ports: 22 and 80.</description></item><item><title>📦 HTB - Obscurity</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-obscurity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/htb-obscurity/</guid><description>Obscurity is my first medium box so I was very happy when I got that root.txt :D
TL;DR Custom Python web server, get source code, get revserse shell, crack user password for custom encryption system, use john to privesc.
Footholds To make things easier, I added the box to my /etc/hosts.
Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with nmap to discover the open ports :
&amp;gt; nmap -A obscurity.htb -o nmap.out Nmap scan report for obscurity.</description></item><item><title>Setup your database with Docker</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/setup-your-database-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/setup-your-database-with-docker/</guid><description>Yeah, I wanted to do one of those for a long time 😁
So, we have to stay at home for the moment, I decided to make a &amp;ldquo;walkthrough&amp;rdquo; about something I used sometimes and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember all the commands. So, let&amp;rsquo;s build our MySQL database within a Docker container 🐳 !
Get the Docker image I will be using the mysql image from the Docker hub.
1 docker pull mysql Run the container For further details, you can read the official documentation for the image on Docker hub.</description></item><item><title>La vulnérabilité Shellshock</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/la-vuln%C3%A9rabilite-shellshock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/la-vuln%C3%A9rabilite-shellshock/</guid><description>Shellshock est une vulnérabilité présente dans bash 4.3 et antérieur. Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une vulnérabilité logicielle qui se base sur de l&amp;rsquo;injection de commande en passant par les variables d&amp;rsquo;environement. C&amp;rsquo;est vachement cool car elle mène à une bonne grosse RCE des familles, donc c&amp;rsquo;est pas négligeable 😘.
Statistiques Quelques statistiques afin d&amp;rsquo;illustrer la portée et l&amp;rsquo;attention portée de la vulnérabilité.
Shellshock a beaucoup été à la mode quand elle est sortie, énormément de trafic a été généré par des botnets lors de tentatives d&amp;rsquo;exploitation de la vulnérabilité.</description></item><item><title>Les pyjails pour les débutants</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/posts/les-pyjails-pour-les-d%C3%A9butants/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/posts/les-pyjails-pour-les-d%C3%A9butants/</guid><description>Introduction Tout d&amp;rsquo;abord qu&amp;rsquo;est-ce qu&amp;rsquo;une &amp;lsquo;pyjail&amp;rsquo; ? Il s&amp;rsquo;agit le plus souvent d&amp;rsquo;un environnement Python 🐍 restreint, c&amp;rsquo;est-à-dire que (comme pour les autres types de &amp;lsquo;jails&amp;rsquo;) certaines fonctions, classes ont été supprimées, ou sont filtrées lors du traitement de l&amp;rsquo;input utilisateur pour bloquer l&amp;rsquo;attaquant.
Ces environnements restreints sont présents lors de CTFs mais c&amp;rsquo;est une catégorie qui nécessite un peu de connaissances avant de s&amp;rsquo;y lancer, mais sont aussi utilisés dans des milieux professionnels afin d&amp;rsquo;éviter de donner l&amp;rsquo;accès à tout le système si un attaquant arrive à entrer sur un serveur SSH par exemple.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/about/</guid><description>French ingeneering student in cybersecurity, I like the web, reverse and assembly.
I participate in CTFs with my team FakeNews. I mostly do the web challenge because this is the easiest when you begin in cybersecurity. 😇
CTF InterIUT 2020 staff 🏁 Norzh CTF 2021 staff 🧭 Why this website The first need of this blog was to help me to remind things as I learn them, and this is a great chance to share my knowledges with others!</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://0xninja.fr/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xninja.fr/projects/</guid><description>I made some projects, some are very interesting, and some are more for learning purposes or testing. I listed here the ones I am the more proud of, but you can get a more exhaustive list by looking here:
https://github.com/OxNinja https://git.fakenews.sh CTF Kit A CLI tool to automate CTF deployment. Focus on the challenges 🚩
SQLi lab A cybersecurity playground to test your 💉 SQL injection skills!</description></item></channel></rss>